Nikhil Maguwala

Nuremberg, Germany

Full Stack Developer & Coding Mentor

Nikhil Maguwala is a Full-Stack Developer with experience developing a website & Apps, Nikhil is fueled by his passion for understanding Full-Stack development. He considers himself a 'forever student. Nikhil believes mindfulness in the workplace is key to success - a tenet he lives out through his interests in yoga, and meditation. Also, Part-time coding tutor at 4Geeks Academy

Work Experience



Full Stack Developer Abaut GmbH, Munich

May 2022 - Present

- Day-to-day responsibility includes Developing Al-powered Web Applications for the company using Angular and Scalable Backend using Python-Flask.
- Maintained a user satisfaction rating of 100% year over year by providing responsive tech support to clients
- Deploying and Managing Jobs in Jenkins using Shell Scripts and Docker.
- Daily routine integration and management tasks to Geo Server Maps and Layers for Construction Clients.
- Than most obvious tasks like Bug Fixing, Critical Coding, Problem Solving Dev Ops, etc.



Full Stack Developer Lanet Team Software Solutions, India August 2020 - February 2022 (1.5 Year)

- Working on React JS, React Native, and Node JS Development
- Worked on Node JS with strict lint check with TS
- Contributed to projects for e-commerce, social media, and navigation applications of large scale
- Done setup of Professional React Native, and Node JS workflows
- Worked with CI/CD pipelines like Travis, Github, etc.
- Worked with DBs like MongoDB, MySQL, and Postgres.
- In addition, Used Docker Containers, Images, AWS, GCP, and Firebase.

Contact Info

Click <u>here</u> for my portfolio

linkedin.com/in/nikhil_maguwala

- nikhilkmaguwala@gmail.com
- nikhilmaquwala.qithub.io
- +49 1632320772

Relevant Skills

- JavaScript, Python, PHP, Shell Script
- React, React Native, Angular, Django, Flask, Node JS
- Jenkins, Docker,
 PostgreSQL, MySQL,
 MongoDB, SQLlite, AWS,
 Firebase

Languages

 German (A2), English (C1), Gujarati (Native), Hindi (Native)

Work Experience



Full Stack Developer Linkage Ventures

May 2021 - July 2021

- Worked on React Native Frontend for Food Delivery App
- Worked on Node JS Backend
- Worked on Web scrapping using Node JS
- Worked with PostgreSQL, Docker, and Linux Deployment



Website And Application Developer Freelance

May 2021 - July 2021

- Made a Website and Application for School for the COVID period.
- Basic Online learning platform for Local School
- Used HTML, JS for Frontend and PHP, and SQL for the Backend
- Lead in the design, development, and implementation of the graphic, layout, and production communication materials
- In School, they are used to making some educational videos and make them online and maintain the web services of the School

Education History



M.Sc. Data Science
<u>Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg</u>
April 2022 - Present



B.E. Computer Engineering

<u>Gujarat Technological University, Gujarat, India</u>

2017 - 2021

GPA: 1.4

Projects

- Image Classification Using Resnet-50 (<u>link</u>)
- Inhale Respiratory
 Disease Prediction Using
 ML (<u>link</u>)
- Application and Website for Gangadhara Primary School (<u>link</u>)

Certification

- Google Data Analytics
 Coursera Currently Learning
- Machine Learning:
 Regression

Coursera - University of Washington

- <u>Python For Data Science</u> IBM - Cognitive Class
- <u>Crash Course for Python</u> Coursera - Google
- Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach

Coursera - University of Washington